Gene.
吉恩
Rouge.
露瓊
Long time no see.
好久不見了
I got attacked by one of Immortal Nine while in Ochrona's custody.
我在被守護局拘留時 遭到不朽九人之一襲擊
They saved me and brought me here.
是他們救了我 帶我來到這裡
I have been relieved of my position as Deputy Director.
我已經被解除次長一職了
Hmm.
嗯
I've heard of it.
我聽說了
I'm really sorry
真的很抱歉
that I put you through a lot.
讓妳吃了不少苦
You two are Ash Stahl and Noid 262 from the Ochrona, right?
兩位是守護局的亞許・斯塔爾 與諾伊德262對吧
Rouge has received a lot of your help.
露瓊受你們關照了
Thank you.
感謝你們
Never mind that, Former Deputy Director.
話說回來 前次長先生
You must be the one behind the scenes
在背地裡從中作梗 妨礙我們調查的人
interfering with our investigation.
就是你吧
Your reputation for competence is well deserved.
幹練之名果然名不虛傳
My strength is my strong curiosity.
我的優點就是好奇心旺盛
Well, what is that?
是說 那是什麼東西
Well,
這個嘛
I have no idea.
我也不太清楚
But,
但是…
there might be the answer I'm looking for.
這底下或許會有我所追求的答案
Do you also want to check it out?
妳想一起去看看嗎
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
In movies,
在電影裡
bad things usually happen after the people went downstairs
像這種通往秘密地下室的樓梯
like these that lead to secret basements.
走下去後通常都會發生很不妙的事
A strong curiosity can be just as dangerous.
旺盛的好奇心同時也是危險要素
You've become quite eloquent.
你也變得伶牙俐齒了呢
What is this?
這到底是…
Is it a library or something?
是圖書館之類的地方嗎
It just looks like a library.
圖書館只是它的表現形式罷了
This is…
這是…
This is the memories of my father,
是我父親…
Dr. Roy Junghardt.
羅伊・容格哈特博士的記憶
What exactly is this place?
這裡到底是什麼地方
A place to keep my father's memories.
是留存父親記憶的場所
In short,
簡單來說
it's like a library of memories.
就是記憶的圖書館吧
I've heard of an external memory system that can store human memories.
我有聽說過 有種外部儲存系統 能用來儲存人類的記憶
Storing even one day's memories requires a huge amount of capacity.
即便是只儲存一天的記憶 也要用上巨大的容量
If this is where all the memories of Dr. Junghardt are stored,
如果說這裡儲存了 容格哈特博士生前的所有記憶
then I am not surprised.
那我一點也不覺得意外
If it were to store my memories, a place the size of a school library would do.
如果要儲存我的記憶的話 高中圖書館大小的地方應該就夠了
I want to investigate something.
我想調查點東西
Do you want to join me?
你們要一起加入嗎
Sure.
好啊
I love it.
我很習慣無聊事了
Rouge.
露瓊
I have to know everything about you.
我必須要瞭解妳的一切
For this,
為此
I need to explore my father's memories.
我得探尋父親的記憶
I want to know more
我也想瞭解
about myself.
瞭解我自己
Who wants to be the priest?
誰要當牧師呢
The crow said, "I'll do it."
烏鴉說"我要當"
I have the Bible,
我手上有聖經
then let me do it.
由我來當吧
Who wants to be the follower?
誰要來當隨從呢
The subject's emotions are gradually developing.
實驗體的情緒正在逐步成長
But they are significantly slower than…
然而 跟我過去 所創造出來的原形涅安相比…
Those of the Proto-Neans I created in the past.
明顯慢了許多
Compared to the slow development of emotions,
對比於情緒的緩慢成長
the physical abilities of the subject far surpass those of humans.
實驗體的體能遠遠地超越了人類
This is superior to other Proto-Neans.
這一點優於其他的原形涅安
In other words,
也就是說
emotional and physical abilities show inverse growth.
情緒與體能的成長比為相反
Interesting.
很有意思
Is this Eva's intention?
這是艾娃有意為之嗎
Or is it just an accident?
又或者只是個偶然呢
We can eat this together.
這個的話 就能一起吃了
It's delicious.
好好吃喔
She has a sense of taste.
擁有味覺
Taking in excess nutrients
攝取多餘的養分
serves no purpose other than pleasure.
並沒有愉悅以外的意義
Someday this child will understand.
這孩子總有一天也會明白吧
Rouge.
露瓊…
So indifferent.
好冷漠
I don't feel any love.
裡面感受不到任何的愛
What does my father think I am?
爸爸到底把我當成是什麼了
Am I just a research subject?
只是普通的研究素材嗎
I have no idea.
我也不清楚
That's why I want to know.
所以才想要知道
Me too.
我也是
Let's continue.
繼續吧
Yes.
嗯
Are you Gene?
你就是吉恩嗎
From today on, you are my son.
從今天開始 你就是我的兒子
Just like that,
就這樣
I became my father's adopted son.
我成為了父親的養子
It's that person.
是那個人
How do you know her?
妳怎麼會認識她
I saw her in my dreams when I got caught at the traveling carnival.
我被抓進移動嘉年華裡時 在夢裡見到過
I can't give it to you.
不能給你
I will never give you the data on Code Eve.
我絕對不會將 CODE EVE的資料交給你的
Let alone give it to the government.
更別說是交給政府了
The Artificial Species Health and Welfare Committee plans to further control Neans, right?
人造種厚生委員會 打算更進一步控制涅安對吧
What's wrong with Code Eve?
CODE EVE怎麼了
It is Code Eve.
是CODE EVE…
Code Eve.
CODE EVE…
I really regret it.
我真的很後悔
It's me who made Neans to become unfree.
讓涅安成為如此不自由的存在
I should never have written Asimov Code that makes them subservient to humans.
根本就不該寫出阿茲莫夫代碼 這種讓他們服從於人類的程式
So Code Eve is the hope.
所以CODE EVE才會是希望
Code Eve can enable Neans
CODE EVE
to be freed from the shackles of Asimov Code.
能夠讓涅安們 從阿茲莫夫代碼的束縛中解放出來
This person
這個人…
is Dr. Eva Kristella.
不就是艾娃・克利絲緹勒博士嗎
If you know her, tell us more.
我說你啊 既然知道就說明一下嘛
She was a brilliant biophysicist who died in an accident 17 years ago.
她是在17年前死於意外的 天才生物物理學家
She served as Dr. Junghardt's assistant,
是容格博士的助手
and created Neans with him.
也是與博士一起創造出涅安的人物
Exactly.
沒錯
She's also my mother.
她同時也是我的母親
The so-called Code Eve
所謂的CODE EVE
is a program that disables Asimov Code
是指能讓阿茲莫夫代碼失效
and frees all Neans from their shackles.
讓所有涅安 從束縛中解放出來的程式
It seems you can be free.
你能得到自由呢
I don't feel anything real.
感受不到什麼真實感
After all, I don't feel particularly unfree right now.
畢竟現在也沒特別感到不自由
You Neans are really dumb.
你們涅安可真是憨直啊
My mother,
我的母親…
Eva Kristella,
艾娃・克利絲緹勒
refused to give the data to the Artificial Species Health and Welfare Committee
拒絕將資料交給人造種厚生委員會
and destroyed it.
並將其銷毀
But it was merely a facade.
但這是表面上的動作
In fact, this is not the case.
實際上卻不是這樣
She secretly hid the data in the id of Proto-Neans created by Father.
她偷偷將資料藏在 父親創造出來的原形涅安的伊德裡
There are a total of nine Proto-Neans,
一共有9具
and they are
他們就是Immortal Nine
Immortal Nine.
不朽九人
After my mother died,
母親亡故後
my father noticed this from the data she had left behind,
父親從她遺留下來的資料中 察覺到這一點
so he began to search for the whereabouts of the Immortal Nine.
於是開始尋找不朽九人的下落
Maybe they noticed what he was doing,
或許是他們注意到了父親的動作
so they killed him.
才會下手殺害父親吧
Why do I recognize your mother?
我為什麼會認得吉恩母親的樣子呢
This is because
這是因為…
Eva Kristella
艾娃・克利絲緹勒她…
is also your mother.
同時也是妳的母親
Rouge.
露瓊
(Episode 8: Nowhere House)
(8 虛幻歸宿)
It's Mother who created you.
是母親創造了妳
Rouge.
露瓊
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事
Why did Father hide this from me?
為什麼父親要向我隱瞞這一點
And why did he observe me?
父親他又是為什麼要觀察我
I have no idea what Father was thinking.
我不清楚父親他在想些什麼
He might just observe you.
他有可能只是在觀察妳
It's hard for me to determine if he loves you.
我也很難斷定他的這些舉動裡 沒有蘊含著對妳的愛
Because he is
因為父親他…
a complicated man.
是個很複雜的人
If…
要是…
If Code Eve can truly free Neans,
要是CODE EVE 真能讓涅安獲得自由的話
isn't that a good thing?
這不是一件好事嗎
Then, Jill and Alter are right.
那吉兒與奧塔不就是正確的嗎
Why do we have to fight the Immortal Nine?
為什麼要跟不朽九人戰鬥呢
Did you lie to me about avenging my father?
說是要為父親報仇 是騙我的嗎
It's true.
是真的
Did I do something wrong?
我是不是做了錯誤的事
No.
沒有做錯
I don't get it.
我不懂…
What do you mean?
哪裡沒有做錯
We have to stop the Immortal Nine.
我們必須要阻止不朽九人才行
You've seen what would happen if Neans were set free now,
要是現在讓涅安得到自由 會發生什麼事
haven't you?
妳也看到了吧
Neans also have various problems.
涅安也有各式各樣的問題
Organizations like CFN and Alter
CFN與奧塔那樣的組織
will surely push for the rights and freedoms they want.
肯定會更進一步 爭取他們想要的權利與自由吧
The rapid changes through violence would plunge the world into chaos
透過暴力所帶來的急遽變化 將會讓世界陷入混沌深淵
and further chaos among the existing Neans.
也會讓現存的涅安更加混亂
But there are some Neans who want a better life.
但也有些涅安想要更好的生活啊
Right.
是啊
That's why we can't cause chaos,
所以我們才不能夠引起混亂
in order to give them a better life.
為了讓他們擁有更好的生活
Now is not the time.
現在還不是時候
Well, may I say something?
那個…能讓我說句話嗎
You are both correct, and neither is wrong.
兩邊都是正確的 兩邊都沒有錯
It's troubling that both freedom and order are essential.
令人傷透腦筋的是 自由與秩序 兩者都是必要之物
Then we have to decide what to choose.
再來就是 自己想要選擇什麼了
Your brother pursues order.
妳哥哥他追求的是秩序
With that in mind, miss,
在這個前提下 妳想要怎麼做
what do you want to do?
小姐
Shall we get started, Deity Officer?
要開始行動嗎 神祇官
Not yet, just stand by.
還沒 就這樣待命
What?
嗯?
Who is that?
那是誰啊
Why don't you deform?
為什麼不變形
Because I'm confused and I wonder what to do.
因為我很迷惘該怎麼做才好
Who are you?
妳又是誰
What do you want?
妳有什麼目的
I want to fight you and destroy you.
跟妳一戰 將妳破壞
Alright, deform now.
來 快變形吧
Fight me.
與我一戰
I don't want to fight.
我不想戰鬥
Attacking someone who doesn't want to fight is of no fun.
攻擊一個不想打的人也沒什麼意思
Are you close to me?
妳是我的誰嗎
I am Cyan,
我是希安
the one who will kill you, and I'm also your younger sister.
是將會殺死妳的人 也是妳的妹妹
Sister?
妹妹
She is…
她是…
Let's meet when you want to fight.
等妳想打的時候 我們再見面吧
Sister.
姊姊
By then,
到時候…
just let me kill you.
要讓我殺掉喔
She kind of looks like you.
感覺她有點像妳欸
The same type of Nean as Rouge.
跟露瓊同一型的涅安
No, that's impossible.
不 這不可能
The one who could make such a thing…
能作出這種東西的…
No way.
真的假的
I was too careless. I didn't think it would happen so fast.
太大意了 想不到居然來得這麼快…
What?
嗯?
Officer Khan.
坎恩管理官…
Ash.
亞許
I got a report of an attack on the Aletheia.
收到了真理部遇襲的報告
Gregory.
葛雷格利
Report the situation.
回報狀況
The Aletheia is currently under attack.
真理部現在正遭受襲擊
I've heard of it.
這我聽說了
Can you get someone to pick me up?
有辦法過來接我嗎
Please take shelter inside the house.
請先進屋回避一下
We are now landing.
現在要進行降落
Annoying!
令人煩躁
Let's get rid of them now, Grauphon.
快點將他們解決掉吧 格勞芬
You don't need to do it.
用不著勞煩妳出手
I think she's the one who attacked the Aletheia.
我想襲擊真理部的人應該是她
She?
她
Jill, she comes to get id back.
吉兒是來搶回伊德的
Sarah, I love you.
莎拉 我愛妳啊
You do too, right?
妳也是吧
Right?
沒錯吧
Did they go to id vault?
他們去了伊德保管庫
Don't come any closer, you monsters.
不要過來 你們這些怪物
Don't you dare touch Sarah.
別想去碰莎拉
She is mine.
她可是我的女人…
Her singing is so beautiful.
她的歌聲如此美妙…
She only loves me.
她只愛著我一個人
She only belongs to me.
是只屬於我的…
Viola never loves you.
拜歐拉根本就沒愛過你
Nius.
紐斯
Achillus.
阿基里斯
Viola.
拜歐拉
Verde.
維杜
I will not fail you.
我不會辜負你們的靈魂
I will surely defeat Jill.
我一定會打倒吉兒的
Miss Rouge.
露瓊小姐
Be careful.
妳要小心
Yes.
嗯
Do you want to come with us?
妳想跟我們一起走了嗎
I see.
這樣啊
Then you are our enemy.
那麼妳就是我們的敵人了
Code Eve will free us Neans from the shackles of Asimov Code.
CODE EVE將使我們涅安 從阿茲莫夫代碼的束縛中解放
Alter hereby declares war on humans.
"奧塔"在此向全人類宣戰
And the final key to decoding Code Eve
以及 解讀CODE EVE的最後關鍵
is the id of you,
那就是露瓊・雷德斯塔
Rouge Redstar.
妳的伊德
I'll take it, Rouge.
交出來吧 露瓊
What a mess here.
真是悽慘
Both sides are going all out.
沒在管目標是誰 根本見人就殺嘛
What you want is not me,
妳想要的並不是我
but my id, right?
是我的伊德對吧
No.
不對
I hope you can fight alongside me with your own will.
我希望妳能以自己的意志 與我共同起身對抗
Stop kidding.
妳少騙人了
I mean it.
我是說真的
You just don't want to face reality.
只是妳對此毫無自覺罷了
I do.
我有啊
I was lost, but now I face the reality.
雖然迷惘 但我還是所有自覺
With my own will,
我要以自己的意志
I will protect the order of this world
守護這個世界的秩序
and safeguard the freedom of humans and the Neans.
守護人類與涅安的自由
You really are a stubborn and silly girl.
一點都不坦率的笨女孩
Please hold on.
請抓穩了
Our people.
是自己人
What?
嗯?
Ash, the backup has arrived.
亞許 援兵到了…
Noid, hey.
諾伊德 喂
Damn.
混帳東西
Who pulled the trigger?
是誰開的槍打中他的
Is he a human?
他是人類嗎
What?
什麼
Is the one who got shot a human?
中槍的是人類嗎
No.
不
He's a Nean.
他是涅安
OK, he's a Nean.
OK 是涅安
Yes.
嗯
Let's go. We'll cover you.
走吧 我們掩護你
No need.
不用了
Get lost.
給我滾
Ash.
亞許…
I don't think
我想…
I can make it.
我應該是不行了…
Ash,
亞許…
your weakness
你的缺點…
is that you can't be honest with yourself.
就是無法坦率地面對自己…
But…
但是…
Okay, don't talk.
好了 你別說話
Why?
這是為什麼呢…
As long as I'm with you,
只要跟你待在一起…
I would forget that I am a Nean.
我就會忘記自己是個涅安…
You should take care of yourself,
你要注意身體健康…
and smoke less…
要減少吸菸量…才行…
Ash.
亞許
Kneel down in front of her.
倒在她的面前吧
Metal Rouge.
鋼鐵露瓊
Do you need any help?
請問需要幫忙嗎
You are…
你是…
Who are you?
你是誰啊
Didn't we go through life and death together in the ruins?
咦 我們不是在遺跡裡生死與共過嗎
Noir.
諾瓦爾
Noir, you are the Jet Black Noir.
諾瓦爾 你是漆黑的諾瓦爾
I haven't been called that in a long time.
很久沒人用這個名字叫我了
You finally figured it out, right?
你終於有那個意思了是吧
Forget it, Silvia.
算了吧 希爾維雅
I am about to extract her id.
我現在正要將她的伊德給挖出來
Then all nine ids will be mine.
這麼一來 九個伊德就會全都落在我的手上
Actually, there's something I have to tell you.
其實有件事 我必須要跟妳說
Really?
真的嗎
About the reply at that time.
關於那時候的回覆
I don't think it's okay to keep you in suspense.
一直吊妳胃口好像也不太好
I've been waiting a long time for it.
我等你這句話很久了
No way.
不會吧
I don't seem to get along with you guys, so I refuse.
我跟你們似乎處不來 所以我拒絕
Sorry.
不好意思啊
Noir.
諾瓦爾…
Tell me what I want to hear.
快說出我想聽的話
Aes.
艾斯…